Electro-Mechanical Technician and Electrician Transitioning to Full Stack Developer

Cover Letter

I am a responsible, creative and motivated individual, with the ease and willingness to learn. I welcome the challenges and goals that your organization might ask. I have excellent interpersonal skills, and have experience working in teams in high pressure environments. In addition, I have the ability to solve problems effectively and reach goals set by the company.

I would have not any problem living abroad of my country if the company requires it.

Experience

2024 - 2024

Bit2me, Alicante, Spain

"Frontend developer with Flutter"

During my cross-platform application development internship with the development team, I played a key role in creating an application using Flutter. This experience enabled me to learn more about the design and functionality of the app, enhancing my cross-platform development skills and deepening my knowledge of Flutter's capabilities.

2023 - 2024

PaynoPain Solutions S.L., Castellón de la Plana, Spain

"Frontend developer with React"

In my front-end development internship with the team, I was actively involved in developing a payment record section into the web-side using React. This role provided me with hands-on experience in both designing and implementing app functionalities, which significantly enhanced my front-end development abilities and deepened my understanding of React's features.

2016 - 2023

Kerajet S.A., Castellón de la Plana, Spain

"International Field Service Engineer"

- Fitting and setup of all printers associated with the Inkjet product lines.
- Sorting out trouble-shooting on-site and finding the breakdowns and repairing printers with complex electrical, mechanical or pneumatic issues.
- Giving technical feedback and sorting the breakdowns out with our customer call center.
- Giving initial and on-going support the customer operator and printer maintenance training.
- Ramp-up and commissioning of machinery.

2015 - 2016

Thistle Seafoods Ltd, Peterhead, Aberdeen, UK

"Electrical Maintenance Engineer"

- Carrying out general maintenance of the factory.
- Installation of general appliances.
- Carrying out preventive maintenance for differents machines.
- Locating and identifying electrical and mechanical breakdowns.
- Modifying electrical plans and electrical panels.



Pedro Monserrat

24/03/1980

Castellón de la Plana Spain

HTTP

www.pedromonserrat.es



+34 629640738



pmonserratsoto@gmail.com



http://www.linkedin.com/in/pedromonserrat/

2013 - 2015

I spent this period of time learning and improving my English doing different English courses in Dublin as well as working as kitchen assistant between at the Dublin airport and La Tasca in Aberdeen.

2008 - 2013

Professional Skills

Windows

Linux

Office

AutoCAD

CX-One

Step 7

SolidWorks

Dialux

Interior Ministry "Correctional Facility Castellón II", Castellón de la Plana, Spain

"Electrician"

- Maintenance of prison.
- Installation of electrical appliances in general with 3 PH and 1 PH.
- Buying of materials and warehouse control.
- Drawing plans with AUTOCAD.
- Responsible for maintaining RACK and installing new points.
- Maintenance and fix of UPS.

2006 - 2008

Climelcas S.L.L., Castellón de la Plana, Spain

"Owner"

- Working on a freelance basis serving Castellón City and Province
- Accounting for personal bookkeeping
- Management of staff members
- All kind of instalations such as domestical, solar panels and electrical panels for the industry.

Languages

Spanish

Catalan

English

Other

Driving License

1999 - 2006

Estudio Cerámico S.L., Castellón de la Plana, Spain

"Electro-mechanical"

- Locating and indentifying electrical and mechanical faults.
- Programming PLC's and Inverters.
- Electro-mechanical repairs to high-speed with PLC-controlled plant, handling equipment with pneumatic and hydraulic control systems.
- Produce performance reports and participating in continuous improvement follow up.
- Knowledge of Electric motors assemble and test.
- Knowledge of PID's controls.
- Ability to fault find using drawings and schematics.
- Knowledge of 3PH/1PH motor controls.
- Planned and preventative maintenance.

Education

2023 / 2024 .- Aula Campus - Burjassot, Valencia

Cross-platform App Developer, HNC

2021 / 2023 .- Aula Campus - Burjassot, Valencia

Front/Back-end Web Developer, HNC

2014 .- ASET International Oil & Gas Trainning Academy, Abedeen, UK

17th Edition IEE Wiring Regulations, City & Guilds 2382

2010 / 2013 .- IES Politècnic, Castellón de la Plana

Electrotechnical, HNC

2010 / 2013 .- IES Serra d'Espadà, Onda, Castellón de la Plana

Automatic Regulation and Control Systems, HNC

1994 / 1999 .- IES Politècnic, Castellón de la Plana

Industrial Electronics, HNC

Another Courses

2024 Artificial Intelligence applied to internationalisation